Susan Caperna Lloyd collection
American Folklife Center, Library of Congress
- Series 8: Oregon
  - Subseries 2: Anti-nuclear movement
    - Portfolio 4: How One Town in Oregon is Saying No to the Bomb, 1982-1983, In 1982, citizen activists in Ashland, Oregon wanted to declare their town a nuclear free zone, following the example of the first nuclear free zones in Great Britain. The individuals spearheading the ballot measure for A
      - Print 7: Philip Davidson, Philip Davidson, actor, Oregon Shakespearean Festival; participant in Peace in the Park. "If, as Shakespeare said, I am 'holding the mirror up to nature' as an actor, it is my function as a human being to say, look, we're in grave danger...we must all pool our energies and act."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-08
      - Print 8: Philip Arnold, Philip Arnold, attorney for Measure 56: "Twenty years ago, it would have been difficult to conceive of a terrorist using a nuclear weapon...Now, I think I can. Twenty years ago, it would have been less likely that a nuclear accident due to human error would cause massive destruction...Now, it seems quite possible. Twenty years ago, it was difficult to contemplate a nuclear war between India and Pakistan...Today, it's conceivable. And our government wants to increase our nuclear arsenal? Doesn't this increase the danger? With the passage of the free zone ordinance in Ashland, we have some hope. Like a lot of laws, our ordinance has both legal and symbolic value. Symbolically, it's important to remember that laws foster new customs and attitudes. With a resultant change of attitude, the free zone concept becomes an acceptable approach for other people to take."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-09
      - Print 9: Father Robert Kruger, Father Robert Kruger, Sacred Heart Parish (Medford), member of Pax Christi: "Pastors have always spoken on moral issues, but these days the moral thinking of the church is running counter to the political thinking of the country. People have been taught the 'just war' theory which says that the citizen follows the direction of the government, unless he is certain the government is wrong. Have there been examples in past history when the church spoke out against the government?...Well, they should have in Nazi Germany, and didn't."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-10
      - Print 10: Michael Leberer, Michael Leberer, actor and director, co-producer of the Nuclear Free Show: Live! "The expectations of patriarchy in our society and the expressions within those expectations are so militaristic and oppressive. Historically, I have a feeling it's reach its peak and may destroy the world. To get involved in the peace movement meant I had to figure out what I was doing first, which I did through theater and writing...and I found that there's a thing about theater; it just won't let you lie to yourself too long." (Note: In June 2019 his name was changed to Michael O'Rourke).; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-11
      - Print 11: Penelope Youngfeather, Penelope Youngfeather, organizer of Candlelight Procession an Silent Vigil for Nuclear Disarmament, Ashland. "The idea for the vigil really started when I was discussing with three friends a book by Jim Wallis, A Call to Conversion, in which he was talking about the fact that the U.S. had a choice in 1945 after the bombings of Hiroshima and Nagasaki: to either ask forgiveness or to justify what they had done by building up the atomic arsenal. It's obvious which course the U.S. took. In realizing this awful truth, I felt the urge to go out to the central plaza of Ashland, drop onto my knees, and publicly ask for forgiveness."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-12
      - Print 12: Michael Touchette, Michael Touchette, businessman. I was outraged when I read recently that during the Vietnam war, Westmoreland almost used nuclear weapons at Khe Sahn. As a Marine, I was there, in a foxhole. Not knowing this at the time, I now realize how expendable an item I had been. In Vietnam, victories were not counted by land possessions or gains, standards set in the past. Instead, the military applied the degrading principle of 'body count.' If the U.S. forces killed six thousand enemy and 'only' lost one thousand in a battle, the U.S. could claim a victory. Can you imagine the body count Westmoreland would have had with the use of nuclear weapons at Khe Sahn? I wonder what would have been an acceptable loss of those of us in the foxholes to insure a U. S. 'Victory'?"; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-13
      - Print 13: Michael and Annie Paup, Michael and Annie Paup, organizers of Peace in the Park; (Annie) member of CALS (Citizen Action for a Lasting Security). (Annie): "Anyone who has a missile in their backyard knows they aren't safe. That's the beauty of the nuclear free zone. When you have to own this weapon and put it in your own city or state, it makes you think twice - do I really want to be a target? If President Reagan wants the MX, have him put it on his ranch in California."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-14
      - Print 14: Marilyn Lenihan, Marilyn Lenihan, nurse and director, Ashland Community Health Center. Spokesperson for Measure 56 (Ashland's Nuclear-Free Zone Ordnance): "Nuclear proliferation is the number one health threat to our community and to every community in the world. Prevention is always the best cure."; AFC 2018/064: SL-23-15
    - Oregon anti-nuclear movement (1 of 2), 1982-1985, 1 folder (Box/folder 31/2)
      - Published version of How One Town in Oregon is Saying No to the Bomb, in Northwest Review, Volume 22, Number 3, Susan Lloyd's photo documentary of Ashland, Oregon peace activists who helped make Ashland a nuclear-free zone. Includes letters from editor, John Witte, 1984, AFC 2018/064: B-01
      - Letter from Don Skinner. A peace activist, he was the initiator of Measure 56 which made Ashland, Oregon one of the first nuclear-free zones in the U.S., Skinner was the subject of AFC 2018/064: SL-23-04.; AFC 2018/064: B-02
      - Publication of photograph of Ashland, Oregon community activist group taken by Susan Lloyd, See AFC 2018/064: SL-23-14.; AFC 2018/064: B-03
      - General local publications: Nuclear Reactions, Peace and Justice Awareness Day, and Clear Actions pertaining to the Ashland, Oregon peace activist movement, AFC 2018/064: B-04
      - Show announcement, letters from galleries, news articles about Susan Lloyd's exhibit, How One Town is Saying No to the Bomb, which toured the U.S. and Europe, AFC 2018/064: B-05
    - Oregon anti-nuclear movement (2 of 2), 1982-1985, 1 folder (Box/folder 31/3)
      - Letter from English gallery forwarding review. Includes flyer identifying exhibit. View of How One Town is Saying No to the Bomb. Includes flyer from exhibit, AFC 2018/064: B-06
      - News story interview about exhibit at On The Wall, The Mail Tribune (Medford, Oregon), page 4B, AFC 2018/064: B-07
      - Original first draft for How One Town is Saying No to the Bomb to accompany exhibition. Final version included in ultimate exhibitions and publications, 1982, AFC 2018/064: B-08
      - Reviews of How One Town is Saying No to the Bomb, Valparaiso University and exhibit at the University of Oregon, Eugene Register Guard. Also exhibition schedule, press release and artist statement, 1984-1985, AFC 2018/064: B-09
      - Schedule of U.S.-wide anti-nuclear activists' protest at National Test Site, Nevada, AFC 2018/064: B-10
      - List of nuclear-free zones in the U.S. and campaigns underway; nuclear-free zones in the world, AFC 2018/064: B-11
    - Ashland, Oregon women activists talk about nuclear war, 1984, AFC 2018/064: SR013; 1 sound cassette
    - [Oregon anti-nuclear movement], 1984-1987, Manuscripts and ephemera related to Oregon anti-nuclear movement.; 1 folder (Box/folder 31/4)
- Series 9: Italian heritage and Italy
  Additional material collected by Lloyd in Italy, related to Holy Week religious ritual, can be found in Series 7.
  - England, France, Italy notebook, 1978, 1 notebook (Box/folder 25/4)
  - Italy, 1978-1988, AFC 2018/064: PH0701-PH0720; 20 color slides (35 mm); 701, Legless man with dog in costume, Rome; 702, Plastic shower curtain in window, Trapani, Sicily; 703, Black mourning clothes hanging from window, Trapani, Sicily; 704, Folk marionettes depicting Crusaders, Trapani, Sicily; 705, "Martini" chairs and pigeons in plaza, Rome; 706, Couple dining with poodle, Rome; 707, Men relaxing in plaza; 708, Men outside traditional bar, Trapani, Sicily; 709, Italian wedding/boat to Island of Capri; 710, Pisa Tower and Carnival flowers, Pisa; 711, Antique Appian Way sign, Terracina; 712, Children playing soccer, Trapani, Sicily; 713, Roma Termini train station, Rome; 714, Porta Bagaglio (porters) in Roma Termini train station, Rome; 715, Soccer team members in train window, Roma Termini train station, Rome; 716, Traditional Arab-influenced fishing boats, Trapani, Sicily; 717, Gondolier chats with tourist as gondola is tied up, Venice; 718, Italian train scene in compartment; 719, On top of Tower of Pisa; 720, Sicilian girl on stairs of Old Town, Trapnai, Sicily. (Box 4)
  - Italy, 1983, AFC 2018/064: SL-10-01 – SL-10-06; 40 black-and-white negatives (120 mm); SL-10-01: Rosario's bedroom, "ex-votos" (photos), funeral notices; Missing 4-6, 9/12/18 scanned #8, 9/12/18 printed #8; SL-10-02: Hanging arm/church floor; Missing 1-4 (blank film), #05 scanned 8/22/2018, printed 8/22/2018; SL-10-03: Hanging arm/church; Frames 9-12 only; SL-10-04: Mosaic and angel; SL-10-05: Monte Cassino, Italy; Missing 7-12, scanned #5 (9/14/18), printed #5; SL-10-06: Italy/Sicily/Ex voto; Missing 7.; Kodak 6049; Ilford FP4 (Box 21)
  - [Original housing from AFC 2018/064: SL-10], 1 folder (Box/folder 37/5)
  - Italian/Sicilian culture and heritage (1 of 3), 1983-2020, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/6)
    - Analysis of Susan Lloyd's study of the folk cult of the Sicilian Black Madonna, Searching for Identity: No Pictures in My Grave: A Spiritual Journey in Sicily, by Elisabetta Marino, University of Rome, British and American Studies, XXIII, pages 97-104, 2018, AFC 2018/064: ZZZ-01
    - Analysis of Susan Lloyd's study of the folk cult of the Sicilian Black Madonna, Ancestral Mothers, Feminine Icons, and Black Madonnas in the Works of Susan Caperna Lloyd by Elisabetta Marino, University of Rome, TestoeSenso, pages 1-12. Includes program from conference, Eye-Centricity and the Visual Cultures of Italy and Its Diaspora, John D. Calandra Italian American Institute, New York, in which Marino gave a paper about Susan's work, based on the analysis in her essay, 2019, AFC 2018/064: ZZZ-02
    - Analysis of Susan Lloyd's study of the folk cult of the Sicilian Black Madonna, The Black Madonna in the Italian American Artistic Imagination by Elisabetta Marino, University of Rome, Acta Neophilogica, 50 (1-2), pages 37-56, 2017, AFC 2018/064: ZZZ-03
    - Creative non-fiction piece by Susan Lloyd, Angela, in VIA (Calandra Institute, New York), Volume 30, Number 2, pages 61-66, about Italian folk culture surrounding death of her young sister. Also program of fifty-second annual Italian American Studies Association conference in Houston, Texas, where Lloyd first read Angela, AFC 2018/064: ZZZ-04
  - Italian heritage and The Baggage film, 2000-2008, 1 folder (Box/folder 26/9)
    - Italian Canadian academic conference programs in which Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, was shown. The film is a family memoir and addresses issues of ethnicity and belonging, AFC 2018/064: Y-01
    - Film script for Susan Lloyd's 2001 film, The Baggage, which was originally titled An Imperfect Family. The film is a memoir using old family photographs and film footage. Centering on the tragic death of her sister, the film addresses issues of ethnicity, immigration, and belonging in Susan Lloyd's Italian American family, AFC 2018/064: Y-02
    - Film script of Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, published in Sweet Lemons. This Canadian journal was edited by Venera Fazio and featured writings on Sicilian and Italian immigrant experiences in the U.S. and Canada, July 1, 2004, AFC 2018/064: Y-03
    - Photocopy of letter from Susan Lloyd to Vincenza Scarpaci in Eugene, Oregon. Vincenza was a consultant on Susan's film, The Baggage. In the letter Susan writes about the reaction to her film at an academic conference on Race, Ethnicity and Migration at the University of Minnesota, November 19, 2000, AFC 2018/064: Y-04
    - Flyer from rough cut of Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, about Italian American immigration. University of Minnesota, November 18, 2000, AFC 2018/064: Y-05
    - Flyer from screening of Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, in forum called Family Stories, Italian American Style, at Southern Oregon University, November 19, 2001, AFC 2018/064: Y-06
    - Final flyer used to promote Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, including press release, AFC 2018/064: Y-07
    - Malafemmina Film Festival program with screening of Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, and Lloyd biography, New York University, New York, May 17-20, 2001, AFC 2018/064: Y-08
    - Amazzoni e Sirene (Amazons and Sirens) twenty third International Women's' Film Festival program featuring Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, Florence, Italy, October 17-22, 2001, AFC 2018/064: Y-09
    - Pesaro, Italy International Film Festival programs featuring Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, June 26-July 2, 2007, AFC 2018/064: Y-10
    - New Italian American Cinema festival program featuring Susan Lloyd's film, The Baggage, Calandra Institute, New York, September 24-27, 2008, AFC 2018/064: Y-11
  - Audiovisual materials related to the film The Baggage (2001), 1965, 1990-2001, 2019
    - Copy of 8mm film element, 1965, AFC 2018/064: MV081; Family movies: Rogue River fishing, Crater Lake (Southern Oregon); Susan Lloyd's father, Ron Caperna, with salmon; sister Shawn Caperna in pool, young brother, Gary Caperna. Footage taken by Amelia Caperna Vorhies when she accompanied her parents, Carolina and Antonio Caperna, to visit her brother, Ron Caperna (Susan Lloyd's father), in Oregon. They came by train from New Jersey.; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Copy of 8mm film element, 1965, AFC 2018/064: MV082; Family movies: World's Fair, Yellowstone National Park, 1965. Footage made when Italian grandparents of Susan Lloyd, Antonio and Carolina Caperna, came by train from New Jersey to Oregon to visit family.; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Copy of 8mm film element, 1965, AFC 2018/064: MV083; Family movies: Grandparents' visit to Southern Oregon. Footage made when Italian grandparents of Susan Lloyd, Antonio and Carolina Caperna, came by train from New Jersey to Oregon to visit family and toured Rogue Valley Country Club in Medford where their son, Ron Caperna, was a gold professional. Ron had grown up in New Jersey as a poor immigrant and learned to play golf by caddying at a New Jersey golf course where, according to legend, the prejudiced caddies repeatedly threw him into Muskenetkong River.; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Camera original element, January 1990, AFC 2018/064: MV079; Christmas Parade of Lights on boats, Lake Mead, Nevada. Shawn Owens' daughter, Holly Owens, and boyfriend going to wedding in Las Vegas area. Shawn, sister of Susan Lloyd, was subject of Susan's 2001 film, The Baggage.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Camera original element, 1990, AFC 2018/064: MV076; Shawn Owens' Palladian-style house, Boulder City, Nevada. Shawn, sister of Susan Lloyd, was subject of Susan's 2001 film, The Baggage. Shawn built luxury homes on the shore of Lake Mead, Nevada.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Camera original element, 1990, AFC 2018/064: MV077; Gail Caperna and Shawn Owens posing, Las Vegas, Nevada. Shawn, sister of Susan Lloyd, was subject of Susan's 2001 film, The Baggage. Gail Caperna, Shawn's mother, was visiting and the family was on their way to a Tom Jones concert.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Camera original element, 1990, AFC 2018/064: MV078; Christmas at Shawn Owens' home, Las Vegas, Nevada. Shawn, sister of Susan Lloyd, was subject of Susan's 2001 film, The Baggage.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Camera original element, 1992, AFC 2018/064: MV080; Shawn Owens' home on Lucerne Street, Lake Mead, Boulder City, Nevada. Shawn, sister of Susan Lloyd, was subject of Susan's 2001 film, The Baggage. She built luxury houses on the shore of Lake Mead, Nevada.; 1 videocassette (VHS-C)
    - Copy of 8mm film element, 2000, AFC 2018/064: MV084; Ron Caperna, Hearthstone Alzheimer's ward, Medford, Oregon. Ron Caperna went into an Alzheimer's ward in 1998 and was filmed as he viewed old family photos and tried to remember his dead daughter, Shawn Owens.; 1 videocassette (VHS)
    - Final edited film master, 2001, AFC 2018/064: MV085; The Baggage (31:09) by Susan Lloyd. Using old family movie footage and photos, the film tells the story of Susan Lloyd's Italian American family and the tragic death of her sister. Edited by Bill Holdeman (Medford, Oregon).; Bill Holdeman; 1 videocassette (MiniDV)
    - Submaster for projection at foreign film festivals, 2001, AFC 2018/064: MV086; The Baggage (31:09) by Susan Lloyd, edited by Bill Holdeman. This sub-master was made for projection at film festivals in Florence (2001) and Pesaro (2007) Italy. See Y-01 to Y-11.; 1 videocassette (Betacam SP)
    - DVD version, 2019, afc2018064_dc004; The Baggage (31:09) by Susan Lloyd. Using old family movie footage and photos, the film tells the story of Susan Lloyd's Italian American family and the tragic death of her sister. Edited by Bill Holdeman (Medford, Oregon).; 5 moving image files (vob, ifo)
  - [ The Baggage ], 2007, Manuscripts and ephemera related to Susan Lloyd's film The Baggage; 1 folder (Box/folder 26/10)
- Series 10: South Africa
  - Recording at Lebowa Rain Queen Modjadji Reserve, Lebowa, South Africa, November 1984, AFC 2018/064: SR009; 1 sound cassette
  - South Africa, 1984, AFC 2018/064: PH0001-PH0020a; 21 color slides (35 mm); 1, Elephant, Kruger Park; 2, South Africa young Xhosa boy, Wild Coast, Transkei Homeland; 3, Young Xhosa girl, Wild Coast, Transkei Homeland; 4, Black mother and baby, Johannesburg; 5, Xhosa children, Wild Coast, Transkei Homeland; 6-7; Zulu folk wood carvers, Swaziland; 8, Zulu folk carvings, Swaziland; 9, Black boy/Zulu painting, Johannesburg flea market; 10, Surfer, Strand Beach, Cape Town; 11, Afrikaner on his folk topiary tree, Johannesburg; 12, Life mask of African tribes, Johannesburg; 13, Non-white shop, Johannesburg; 14, Zulu boy with jewelry, Swaziland; 15, Street scene, Johannesburg; 16, Whites only sign, Johannesburg; 17, Zulu stick dancing boys, Swaziland; 18, Black Santa Claus, Umtata, Transkei Homeland; 19, Street cleaners, Johannesburg; 20, Sky Lloyd with Xhosa children, Transkei Homeland; 20a, Building, Johannesburg. (Box 1)
  - South African women, 1984, AFC 2018/064: PH0021-PH0040; 20 color slides (35 mm); 21, Black maid with Susan Lloyd's baby, Johannesburg; 22, Janitress, Johannesburg mall; 23, Zulu woman wearing beadwork, Swaziland; 24, Black woman, Johannesburg street; 25, Bernadette Mosala, Director of Council of Churches, Johannesburg; 26, Lucy Mvubelo, Secretary-General of the National Clothing Workers Union, Johannesburg; 27, Sue Williamson, artist, Cape Town; 28, Natalie Knight, playwright, Johannesburg; 29, Maureen Puput, tea girl, Johannesburg; 30, Helen Joseph, first under house arrest, Johannesburg; 31, Johannesburg street scene; 32, Barbara Coetzee, unemployed, Johannesburg Black suburb; 33, Woman with baby on back Johannesburg street; 34, Denise Baker, Johannesburg Black school; 35, Black nanny with white children, Cape Town; 36, Black women, Johannesburg suburb; 37, Zulu women, Swaziland; 38, Xhosa woman/foil folk art, crossroads camp, Cape Town; 39, Parking lot scene, Cape Town; 40, Woman on Johannesburg street. (Box 1)
  - South Africa Modjadji Rain Queen and Reserve, 1984, AFC 2018/064: PH0041-PH0080; 40 color slides (35 mm); 41, Entrance to Modjadji Reserve, Lebowa, South Africa; 42-43, Children of Rain Queen's wives; 44, The Modjadji cycad forest; 45, Rainmaking stick, Modjadji Reserve; 46, Mokope Modjadji V; 47, Petitioner to Mokope Modjadji; 48-50, Cycad nursery, Modjadji Reserve; 51, Modjadji's wives and Shane Lloyd (Susan Lloyd's son); 52, Mokope Modjadji in rondavel doorway; 53, Cycad cone and seeds, Modjadji nursery; 54, Cycad seeds, Modjadji nursery; 55, Drying cycad seeds, Modjadji nursery; 56, Mokope Modjadji with photographer's son; 57, Display at Modjadji nursery; 58-60, Rain Queen Mokope Modjadji in isolation; 61-64, Cycad forest; 65-68, Children of Rain Queen's wives; 69-75, Modjadji nursery; 76-80, Extracting cycad seed from cone. (Box 1)
  - South Africa, 1984, AFC 2018/064: PH0081-PH0100; 20 color slides (35 mm); 81, Johannesburg skyscraper; 82, Johannesburg street scene; 83, Ice cream vendor and children, Cape Town; 84, Black woman and child in surf, Transkei Wild coast; 85, Black child, Crossroads camp, Cape Town; 86, Flea market and nuclear plants, Johannesburg; 87, Black-only segregated beach, Durban; 88, White jogger on Black-only segregated beach, Durban; 89, Unconscious man roadside, Swaziland; 90, Assisting unconscious man roadside, Swaziland; 91, Johannesburg street scene; 92, Waiting for a bus, Johannesburg; 93, Warning sign for servants, Johannesburg; 94, Man reading newspaper, Johannesburg; 95, Swazi fried chicken sign, Johannesburg; 96, Afrikaans news stand, Johannesburg; 97, Xhosa children, Transkei Homeland; 98, Acacia tree, Transvaal; 99, Ant hill, Transvaal; 100; Farm and mountains, Northern Transvaal. (Box 1)
  - South Africa, 1984, AFC 2018/064: SL-30-01; 21 black-and-white negatives (35 mm); Complete.; Kodak (Box 23)
  - [Original housing from SL-30], 1 folder (Box/folder 38/10)
  - South Africa notebooks (1 of 2), 1984, Miscellaneous jottings, Rain Queen Modjadji nursery history. Sites visited in South Africa, Black print shop worker (Maureen Paput) interview notes, Afrikaner foods, Cape Town artist-activist Sue Williamson interview, miscellaneous names/addresses. Impressions of first arrival in South Africa, Johannesburg Black culture, experiences with Afrikaner family hospitality, Swaziland, street music, interview with Black hotel chef.; 3 notebooks (Box/folder 31/5)
  - South Africa notebooks (2 of 2), 1984, Interviews with women activists, Swaziland, Transkei Homeland hike, Sue Williamson, Crossroads, Rain Queen.; 1 notebook (Box/folder 31/6)
  - Portfolio 7: The Modjadji, Rain Queen of Lebowa, 1984, A matriarchal line known as the Modjadji has ruled Lebowa province in northeastern South Africa for five hundred years. Once a woman inherits the throne from a predecessor, she becomes a Modjadji for life and must remain in the Royal kraal, never leaving. Her handmaidens live in the kraal with her and their children; mating with nobles, they are her symbolic children. In annual autumn ceremonies, the Modjadji officiates over rain making dances and ritual performances. She also reigns over the sacred cycad tree forest in the Modjadji Reserve near her kraal. On site is an active nursery where the cycad seeds are cultivated; folk belief associates these red seeds with the Modjadji's powers of fertility. Susan Lloyd visited Mokope Modjadji V, the fifth Rain Queen, with her five-month old son, Shane Lloyd. Mokope lived in seclusion in the Royal Kraal in Khetihakone Village, Lebowa, South Africa, and allowed her to also photograph the cycad forest and cycad plants and seeds in the nursery. It was rare, at the time, for an outsider to secure permission to meet and photograph the Modjadji. Susan Lloyd brought Mokope a U.S. flag as a gift. Mokope insisted that she be photographed with her son and the flag. The photographs in this portfolio were made during Susan Lloyd's visit with Mokope Modjadji V.; 1 portfolio (12 photographs): color Ultrachrome archival inkjet prints; 19 x 13 inch (Box 49)